Reliable, creative, energetic, and determined individual dedicated to motivating and engaging middle and high school students to study language, literature, and writing. One with a multitude of experience in composing concise, creative lessons, implementing differentiated instruction, and fostering a positive learning environment.

Education

B.A. Secondary English Education

Point Park University Pittsburgh, PA – 2014

Overall GPA: 3.73 Education GPA: 3.95

Graduated with Magna cum Laude Status

Active Member, Pi Lambda Theta; Dean's List Honors

7-12 Pennsylvania State Teacher's Certificate

7-12 Ohio State Educator License - 4 Year Resident Certificate

Key Qualifications

- o Strong lesson planning
- o Communication skills
- o Published Author (Ralph Munn Anthology)
- o Technology integration
- o Differentiated instruction
- o Ability to form strong positive rapport with students
- o Multitude of experience with teaching Shakespeare
- o AP Literature teaching experience

Teaching Experience

English Teacher

August 2014 - Present

Horizon Science Academy Toledo - Toledo, OH

- Assumed responsibility of AP English Literature, AP Study Hall, English II, and English II Honors. (2015-2016 school year)
- Planned and conducted lessons for AP English Literature, English II, and English II Honors. (2015-2016 school year).
- Assumed responsibility of 12th grade College Composition, English IV, English IV Honors, and 9th grade Reading and Writing Workshop Classes. (2014-2015 school year).
- Planned and conducted lessons for College Composition, English IV, Writing Workshop, and Saturday School Language Arts Study. (2014-2015 school year).
- Served as the 10th grade GLC head (Grade Level Committee).
- Served as a leadership member on the HSAT PBIS team monthly review of data and discussion of meeting tier 1 progress.
- Implemented technology into daily lessons through the use of a Smart Board, Prezi, and PowerPoint presentations.
- Weekly contact with parents: e-mail, phone calls, home visits, and bi-monthly parent-teacher conferences.
- Modified/differentiated instruction to meet the needs of IEP students.
- Designed and enforced a class wide behavior and achievement recognition system.
- Held after school tutoring sessions for English twice a week.
- Assumed responsibility of a small group of students and held weekly advisory meetings.

Colleen Clark

3620 Douglas Road. Toledo, Oh 43613

412-478-5430 ceclark692@gmail.com

- Attended weekly staff, department, and grade level coordinator meetings.
- Entered attendance and grades on a daily basis.
- Collaborated on, planned, and facilitated a series of activities for the Horizon Science Academy Anime Club.
- Taught and participated in the Ivy League Mentorship Program. (2014-2015 school year).
- Attended daily duties: Hallway monitoring, bus, breakfast, and lunch duty.
- Built and maintained relationships with students, parents, the English department, counselors, and administration.
- Completed research and assessments to aid in recommending students for IEPs or 504 plans.
- Attended a series of IEP meetings.
- Assessed students formally and informally.
- Daily reflection and adjustment of lesson plans.
- Monitored study hall for PARCC testing.
- Administered the English IV and English II EOCs (End of course) exams.
- Attended Concept Schools professional development sessions (both school and district wide).
- Attended PBIS tier 1 training (11 contact hours).
- Attended the AP English Literature Summer Institute (30 contact hours).

Student Teacher

January 2014- April 2014

Pittsburgh Public School District - Carrick High School, Pittsburgh, PA

Student Teacher January 2014- April 2014

Pittsburgh Public School District - Carrick High School, Pittsburgh, PA

- Assumed responsibility of 9th grade CAS English, 11th grade AP English Language and Literature, homeroom, and Journalism.
- Planned and conducted lessons for AP English, CAS English, and Journalism classes.
- Co-taught Shakespeare unit for CAS classes.
- Implemented technology into classroom through the use of the ELMO document camera and available computer labs.
- Designed and enforced a class wide recognition system for behavior management.
- Attended professional development meetings both school wide and district wide.
- Built and maintained relationships with students, the English department, counselors, and cooperating teacher.
- Assessed students formally and informally.
- Daily reflection, discussions with cooperating teacher, and adjusting of lessons to enhance the overall impact.
- Organized activities and co-taught the Marvel Comics Club.
- Facilitated publication of the school newspaper (The Carrickulum)
- Contacted parents in regards to student progress.
- Taught Prezi software to the English Department.
- Organized and taught after school and Saturday AP Prep Sessions.

Relevant Work Experience

Colleen Clark

3620 Douglas Road. Toledo, Oh 43613

412-478-5430 ceclark692@gmail.com

Mentor

May 2013 – May 2014

- Propel Charter Schools and Point Park University CollegeNOW Pittsburgh, PA
- Documented and evaluated student progress.
- Tutored mentee with English assignments.
- Provided support and encouragement in regards to mentee's college career.
- Built and maintained relationship with mentee.
- · Actively participated in a school wide mentoring session with all College NOW Propel Charter School students
- Held advising sessions each semester to plan college class schedules for students.

Tutor

September 2013 – November 2013

Steel Valley High School - Munhall, PA

- Tutored students in History, English, and Keystone Exam prep.
- Constructed lesson plans and interactive activities to present topics in a new way.
- Conducted a case study on a single student to evaluate the student as a learner and the effectiveness of lessons.
- Attended meetings with the principal, vice principal, and faculty to discuss student needs and student progress.

Conversation Partner

Spring 2013

Certificate of Participation obtained

ELS Language Centers - Pittsburgh, PA

- Attended weekly meetings with a Saudi Arabian ELL student.
- Provided tutoring for college assignments.
- Kept detailed notes on ELL student progress.
- Created and learned ways to communicate effectively.
- Familiarized with Saudi Arabian culture; discussed and shared American culture with the ELL student.